{
    "time": 10,
    "React": [
        {
            "question": "1. What is useEffect in React?",
            "option1": "a React hook",
            "option2": "function to set visual effects in React",
            "option3": "what is React",
            "option4": "a React key",
            "correctresponse": "a React hook",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "2. Which method in React component is called after the component is rendered for the first time?",
            "option1": "componentWillMount",
            "option2": "componentDidMount",
            "option3": "componentWillReceiveProps",
            "option4": "componentDidUpdate",
            "correctresponse": "componentDidMount",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "3. What is the purpose of props in React?",
            "option1": "to create React components",
            "option2": "to manage state in React",
            "option3": "to pass data from parent to child components",
            "option4": "to handle user events in React",
            "correctresponse": "to pass data from parent to child components",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "4. What is the correct way to handle forms in React?",
            "option1": "Using refs",
            "option2": "Using event listeners",
            "option3": "Using state",
            "option4": "Using props",
            "correctresponse": "Using state",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "5. Which of the following lifecycle methods is invoked just before a component is unmounted and destroyed?",
            "option1": "componentWillUnmount",
            "option2": "componentDidMount",
            "option3": "componentWillMount",
            "option4": "componentDidUpdate",
            "correctresponse": "componentWillUnmount",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "6. In React, what is the purpose of the 'key' attribute when rendering lists of elements?",
            "option1": "It specifies the order of elements in the list",
            "option2": "It helps React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed",
            "option3": "It determines the style of elements in the list",
            "option4": "It provides a unique identifier for each element in the list",
            "correctresponse": "It helps React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "7. How can you update the state of a component in React?",
            "option1": "Directly modify this.state",
            "option2": "Use setState() method",
            "option3": "Use forceUpdate() method",
            "option4": "Use props",
            "correctresponse": "Use setState() method",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "8. What is the purpose of the render() method in a React component?",
            "option1": "To perform side effects and data fetching",
            "option2": "To handle user input",
            "option3": "To specify the layout and appearance of the component",
            "option4": "To render JSX elements to the DOM",
            "correctresponse": "To render JSX elements to the DOM",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "9. What is the difference between state and props in React?",
            "option1": "State is immutable, while props can be changed",
            "option2": "State is local to a component, while props are passed from parent to child components",
            "option3": "State is used for internal data management, while props are used to pass data between components",
            "option4": "There is no difference, they are used interchangeably",
            "correctresponse": "State is used for internal data management, while props are used to pass data between components",
            "time": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "10. What is the purpose of React Fragments?",
            "option1": "To create reusable React components",
            "option2": "To improve performance by reducing the number of DOM elements",
            "option3": "To group multiple React elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM",
            "option4": "To handle errors in React components",
            "correctresponse": "To group multiple React elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM",
            "time": 1
        }
    ]
}